{
    "questionList":[{
        "id":"1",
        "question":"Which one is the longest river in Gujarat?",
        "optionA":"(A) Sabarmati",
        "optionB":"(B) Mahi",
        "optionC":"(C) Narmada",
        "optionD":"(D) Tapi",
        "Answer": "(C) Narmada",
        "CorrectOption":"C"
    },
    {
        "id":"2",
        "question":"On which river the Sardar Sarovar Dam is built?",
        "optionA":"(A) Daman Ganga River",
        "optionB":"(B) Tapti River",
        "optionC":"(C) Sabarmati River",
        "optionD":"(D) Narmada River",
        "Answer": "(D) Narmada River",
        "CorrectOption":"D"
    },{
        "id":"3",
        "question":"Sabarmati Ashram was built in the year?",
        "optionA":"(A) 1917",
        "optionB":"(B) 1919",
        "optionC":"(C) 1920",
        "optionD":"(D) 1922",
        "Answer": "(A) 1917",
        "CorrectOption":"A"
    },{
        "id": "4",
        "question":"Total number of Districts in Gujarat?",
        "optionA":"(A) 28",
        "optionB":"(B) 33",
        "optionC":"(C) 35",
        "optionD":"(D) 39",
        "Answer":"(B) 33",
        "CorrectOption":"B"
    },{
        "id":"5",
        "question":"Which city is also known as the Diamond City of India?",
        "optionA":"(A) Rajkot",
        "optionB":"(B) Surat",
        "optionC":"(C) Gandhinagar",
        "optionD":"(D) Ahmedabad",
        "Answer": "(B) Surat",
        "CorrectOption":"B" 
    },
    {
        "id":"6",
        "question":"Who had built the Sun Temple of Modhera?",
        "optionA":"(A) Bhimdev I",
        "optionB":"(B) Karandev I",
        "optionC":"(C) Siddharaj Jaisinh",
        "optionD":"(D) Kumarapala",
        "Answer": "(A) Bhimdev I",
        "CorrectOption":"A"
    },{
        "id":"7",
        "question":"The UNESCO heritage site \"Rani ki vav\" is located in which district?",
        "optionA":"(A) Bharuch",
        "optionB":"(B) Amreli",
        "optionC":"(C) Bhavnagar",
        "optionD":"(D) Patan",
        "Answer": "(D) Patan",
        "CorrectOption":"D"
    },{
        "id": "8",
        "question":" when did gujarat Formation?",
        "optionA":"(A) 15 Aug 1947",
        "optionB":"(B) 1 May 1960",
        "optionC":"(C) 1 May 1980",
        "optionD":"(D) 23 Sep 1990",
        "Answer":"(B) 1 May 1960",
        "CorrectOption":"B"
    },{
      "id":"9",
      "question":"The endangered Asiatic lions can be found in which National Park?",
      "optionA":"(A) Gir National Park",
      "optionB":"(B) Orang National Park",
      "optionC":"(C) Kaziranga National Park",
      "optionD":"(D) Ranthambore National Park",
      "Answer":"(A) Gir National Park",
      "CorrectOption":"A"
    },{
      "id":"10",
      "question":"Which one is an ancient Indus valley civilization city located in Gujarat?",
      "optionA":"(A) Harappa",
      "optionB":"(B) Mehargarh",
      "optionC":"(C) Lothal",
      "optionD":"(B) Mehargarh",
      "Answer":"(C) Lothal",
      "CorrectOption":"C"
    },{
      "id":"11",
      "question":"Which one is the latest site to include as World Heritage Site in 2021?",
      "optionA":"(A) Surkotada",
      "optionB":"(B) Ahmedabad",
      "optionC":"(C) Dholavira",
      "optionD":"(D) Rani ki Vav",
      "Answer":"(A) Surkotada",
      "CorrectOption":"A"
    },{
      "id":"12",
      "question":"Which one was the first capital of Gujarat Sultanate?",
      "optionA":"(A) Ahmedabad",
      "optionB":"(B) Anhilwad Patan",
      "optionC":"(C) Muhammadabad",
      "optionD":"(D) None of the above",
      "Answer":"(B) Anhilwad Patan",
      "CorrectOption":"B"
    },{
      "id":"13",
      "question":"Which Mughal Emperor was born at Dahod in Gujarat?",
      "optionA":"(A) Akbar",
      "optionB":"(B) Shah Jahan",
      "optionC":"(C) Aurangzeb",
      "optionD":"(D) Bahadur Shah I",
      "Answer":"(C) Aurangzeb",
      "CorrectOption":"C"
    },{
      "id":"14",
      "question":"In which year, the construction of Sardar Sarovar Dam was started?",
      "optionA":"(A) 1982",
      "optionB":"(B) 1985",
      "optionC":"(C) 1987",
      "optionD":"(D) 1990",
      "Answer":"(C) 1987",
      "CorrectOption":"C"
    },{
      "id":"15",
      "question":"Total number of memebers in the Gujarat Legislative Assembly is............",
      "optionA":"(A) 156",
      "optionB":"(B) 171",
      "optionC":"(C) 180",
      "optionD":"(D) 182",
      "Answer":"(D) 182",
      "CorrectOption":"D"
    },{
      "id":"16",
      "question":"Which poet had been named as Raashtreeya Shaayar by Mahatma Gandhi",
      "optionA":"(A) Umashankar Jethalal Joshi",
      "optionB":"(B) Avinash Vyas",
      "optionC":"(C) Jhaverchand Meghani",
      "optionD":"(D) Govardhanram Tripathi",
      "Answer":"(C) Jhaverchand Meghani",
      "CorrectOption":"C"
    },{
      "id":"17",
      "question":"Gujarat is the ________ largest state in Indian by area",
      "optionA":"(A) third",
      "optionB":"(B) fourth",
      "optionC":"(C) fifth",
      "optionD":"(D) sixth",
      "Answer":"(C) fifth",
      "CorrectOption":"C"
    },{
      "id":"18",
      "question":"Who is the first person from Gujarat to received Padma Vibhushan award",
      "optionA":"(A) U.N. Dhebar",
      "optionB":"(B) Gulzari Lal Nanda",
      "optionC":"(C) Indraprasad Gordhanbhai Patel",
      "optionD":"(D) Vikram Ambalal Sarabhai",
      "Answer":"(D) Vikram Ambalal Sarabhai",
      "CorrectOption":"D"
    },{
      "id":"19",
      "question":"The Vansda National Park is located in which district",
      "optionA":"(A) Navsari",
      "optionB":"(B) Junagadh",
      "optionC":"(C) Bhavnagar",
      "optionD":"(D) Jamnagar"
      "Answer":"(A) Navsari",
      "CorrectOption":"A"
    },{
      "id":"20",
      "question":"As of 2021, total number of wildlife sanctuaries in Gujarat is",
      "optionA":"(A) 22 sanctuaries",
      "optionB":"(B) 23 sanctuaries",
      "optionC":"(C) 24 sanctuaries",
      "optionD":"(D) 25 sanctuaries",
      "Answer":"(B) 23 sanctuaries",
      "CorrectOption":"B"
    }
}